if you haven't been paying attention
Nike just released their own line of
strength gear and their grind bumper
plates are some of my favorites on the
market right now they look amazing and
they're available at a really sweet
price point I'm pretty pumped for this
video today so let's get right to
[Music]
it what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the Barb and garage gym and for today's
video I've got a pair of 45 lb Nike
grind bumper plates that I'm going to be
breaking down for youall you don't know
how this process works in this video
today I'm going to tell you everything
there is to know about these plates from
the price to some pros and cons and then
of course who should or maybe should not
make this purchase but before I do that
I got to let yall know that we've
reviewed a whole lot of other bumper
plates on barb. comom and guess what we
have a best list you want to check that
out all you got to do is search barbend
best bumper plates that article is going
to pull right up for you and you can
find out for yourself ST which ones we
like the
best okay so what are crumb bumper
plates for so for those who don't know
crumb bumper plates made from recycled
rubber so they're going to have more
bounce than virgin rubber plates will
but they're also going to be cheaper so
if you're on a tight budget you know
crumb bumper plates are a really solid
way to go about it they're going to be
better for the environment as well since
they are in fact made from recycled
materials and then another thing here is
that the thickness they're thicker than
virgin plates are and that could be good
or bad depending on you know your
experience level how much weight you're
trying to lift and everything like that
so with these bumper plates I really
like the fact that they're made from
Nike you know leftover shoes that's
great for the environment you know
eco-friendly and everything like that it
does in fact lead to you know more
bounce than what you'll find with some
virgin rubber plates I'll showcase that
in a second so you can really understand
what I'm talking about but you know that
could be good for some people I also
really like how the actual collar right
here it's co- molded which basically
means that this is just one piece
there's really not a lip at all in
between the plate and the actual collar
which is something that I can definitely
get behind and you probably can as well
these are also competitively priced so
one pair of 45lb bumpers it's going to
cost you about 220 bucks which is about
the market Standard and on top of that
they're also really easy to get you can
go down your local Dick Sporting Goods
and just snag some right there which is
a really cool thing now with the cons
there's aside from you know the lack of
full sets I don't really think there's
anything you know negative about these
specific plates having the full sets
would be really nice but kind of is what
it is you know that extra bounce like I
said may not be ideal for everybody you
could you know either a injure yourself
if you're not careful but also kind of
cause some damage to your surroundings
so it's definitely just something you
want to be you know extra careful with
and then also you know that thickness
like I talked about so the thicker your
weight plates are you know the less room
room you're going to have overall on
your loading sleeves of your barbell but
also for it's mainly for people who are
you know doing Olympic weightlifting and
are very good at it and understand the
intricacies and everything about
barbells and everything like that but
the thicker your weight plates are could
you know negatively impact the Whip or
you know the bounce that occurs mid lift
on your barbell so that's definitely
something that you want to be aware of
as
well okay so once again these grind
bumper plates are not available in a
full set but the prices are honestly
really competitive okay so once again a
pair of these 45lb plates from Nike are
going to cost you about 220 bucks now
that's pretty much the market average
you know with rep Fitness their are
about 214 and Rogue theirs are 160 up
front but then obviously with shipping
and taxes and everything it winds up
balancing you know right back out so at
the end of the day I mean yeah these are
really competitive you can't really go
wrong with that price
tag all right so I really enjoy the
aesthetic of these plates something
about it just looks great all the little
specs but something I think is that is
really cool is that you know as the
years go on as Nike you know continues
to make these products the actual color
is going to change for the buffer plates
I think that's cool all depends on you
know the colorways of the year and what
excess waste they have and everything
like that so that's pretty sweet now I
really do like the fact that you know
this collar right here is basically co-
molded you know like I said earlier
there's really no seam right there and
that's something that you definitely
want for durability purposes and
speaking of that there's also really no
sign of a seam on the actual you know
profile of the plates now a little bit
right here but that's just kind of
standard across all bumper plates where
you kind of have that little like
tapered down Edge right there but still
nothing to make me think that you know
the the durability is going to be an
issue with these plates these are you
know a little over 3 in thick about 3.15
in so they're definitely thicker than
you know virgin rubber plates Nikes are
about 2.98 not that far off but you know
over time as you know pack on some
weight that could make a difference in
the whip don't forget that all right now
another thing here is that these plates
are listed as a plus minus 1% weight
accuracy that's pretty average across
the market but just to you know test it
out and make sure youall know these are
not fake these are real plates we're
going to weigh it right here all right
so let's go ahead and see if it'll stand
on its own right
there it's not staying for me let's see
if we can get this
going all right 46 lbs that's not a big
deal at all I'd rather it be a little
bit heavier than a little bit lighter
you know what I'm saying so that's
really cool right there these also have
a durometer rating of 65 now that's way
off from the 88 durometer rating on the
Nike virgin rubbers so what I want to do
right now is just kind of pull this away
and do a quick drop test with Rogues
bumper plates I have right here which
also share you know the 88 drometer
rating so just one second all right so
like I said we got the Nike bumpers
right here the grind bumpers on this
barbell and I got the Rogue Echo bumpers
right here on this back one all right so
just go ahead and pick this up and just
show you how much bounce you can expect
this is just a normal you know waist
height
whatever that's you know kind of a lot
of balance you can only imagine how much
it would be if I had it you know up here
right racked let me make sure that
doesn't roll away on us now let's show
you these Rogue ones right here which do
share you know that same durometer
rating as Nike's other bumper
plates I know that was really loud but
you see how that was just a dead bounce
that's where that durometer rating
really comes into play so if you want to
avoid you know that super Super bounce
right there and you know prevent any
type of injury from the bar bouncing
into you or hitting other equipment or
anything like that then yeah you know
crumb bumpers aren't going to be the
best bet for you in which case you'd
want to go after you know something like
this right here I think these are great
for any anybody who wants some
highquality bumper plates that are also
really easily accessible remember you
can head down to your local Dick
Sporting Goods and probably be able to
walk out with them right then and there
they're also competitively priced 220
bucks for a pair it's really not a bad
deal plus if you're somebody who's very
eco-friendly I think you're going to
love the fact these are made from
recycled rubber now only reason in my
opinion to not purchase these it really
just boils down to personal preference
you know maybe you don't like the extra
thickness maybe you don't like that
extra bounce in that case I would go
find some you thinner and thinner plates
that also have you know more of a dead
bounce that's all I got for yall today
on the Nike grind bumper plates out of
all their gear they've released lately
these are probably my personal favorite
thanks for watching hope this video was
really helpful and I was able to answer
any questions you may have about these
bumper plates as always stay posted for
my next video but for now head over to
barb. comom cuz we have a full written
article about these plates but I think
you should go and check out all you got
to do is search barbend Nike grind
bumper plate review it's going to pull
right up for you and you can read over
everything we talked about here today
I'll catch youall next
[Music]
time